<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>knob on Daniele Antonioli</title>
    <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tags/knob/</link>
    <description>Recent content in knob on Daniele Antonioli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Daniele Antonioli</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://francozappa.github.io/tags/knob/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>KNOB Attack FAQ</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-faq/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m trying to address some discussion points and misconceptions about the KNOB attack.
Attribution  Researchers from CISPA discovered the KNOB attack
 Partially true. The KNOB attack was discovered by myself (Daniele Antonioli) from SUTD, Nils Ole Tippenhauer from CISPA, and Kasper Rasmussen from the University of Oxford. In particular, I&amp;rsquo;ve identified the vulnerability back in May 2018 while I was working with Kasper on Nearby Connections at the University of Oxford, and I wrote the first exploit in October 2018 while I was visiting Nils (my former advisor at SUTD) at CISPA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KNOB Attack Code for E0 and Slides from USEC19 are Online</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-repo2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-repo2/</guid>
      <description>The code that we developed to validate and brute force E0 encryption keys is online.
The slides of my KNOB attack USEC19 talk are also online. As we can see from the slides, the KNOB attack is not conducted while two Bluetooth devices are pairing, but when two devices are connecting (establishing a new encrypted session). Bluetooth (BR/EDR) is a technology with a pair-once connect-multiple-times paradigm. For example, you pair your smartphone with your car once, and then every day you connect the two and the devices negotiate a new (fresh) encryption key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KNOB Attack Repository is Online</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-repo/</guid>
      <description>Our KNOB repository is online, and it includes our PoC.
For more information visit knobattack.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Negotiation Of Bluetooth (KNOB) Attack</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-announce/</guid>
      <description>The embargo is over! The information about The KNOB is Broken: Exploiting Low Entropy in the Encryption Key Negotiation Of Bluetooth BR/EDR, including our research paper, CVE details, and media coverage, are publicly available at knobattack.com</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>