<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>talk | Daniele Antonioli</title>
    <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tag/talk/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://francozappa.github.io/tag/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>talk</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023 Daniele Antonioli</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://francozappa.github.io/media/icon_hufd6449924b8771808a89b636be1cd7b0_295644_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>talk</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tag/talk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>SecMT&#39;21 Talk About Security of Proximity Services</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2021/secmt21-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2021/secmt21-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad to give a talk at the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://spritz.math.unipd.it/events/2021/ACNS_Workshop/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SecMT&#39;21&lt;/a&gt;
workshop on mobile system security
co-located with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sulab-sever.u-aizu.ac.jp/ACNS2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ACNS&#39;21&lt;/a&gt;
conference.
Students can register to SecMT for &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt; by filling this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfwNOLR8AJmbJo5F954hTXvhsTfKXE3FvTVFr-OLmLcbWmTyg/viewform&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk title&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is Hard to Secure Mobile Proximity Services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk abstract&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile devices such as phones, tablets, and wearables enable proximity
services on a large scale. These services use wireless technologies (such as
Wi-Fi and Bluetooth) to connect users within a specific range and exchange
information. Proximity information ranges from general-purpose files and
contacts to privacy-preserving COVID-19 proximity identifiers. Since these
services affect millions of mobile users worldwide, their security against
cyber threats is paramount. It is not pleasant if an attacker in proximity (or
even remotely) can eavesdrop on private communication or tamper with personal
data. However, adopting (even essential) security mechanisms for proximity
services is easy in theory but pretty hard in practice. For example, it is
challenging to provide confidentiality and authenticity while at the same time
provide energy-efficient and accurate proximity tracing. On top of that, a
usable proximity service has to scale well with the number of users and
provide the same quality of services across different software and hardware
ecosystems (e.g., Android and iOS) and usage condition (e.g., indoor and
outdoor). In this talk, we look at two commercial proximity services. First,
Google&amp;rsquo;s Nearby Connections (NC) is an API to connect Android devices using a
combination of Wi-Fi and Bluetooth and without requiring an Internet
connection. Second, Google/Apple&amp;rsquo;s Exposure Notification (EN) framework. EN
powers most COVID-19 contact-tracing mobile applications in Europe, including
the ones used in Italy, Germany, and Switzerland. Throughout the talk, the
audience will learn, among others, real-world proximity services&#39;
architectures, pitfalls, vulnerabilities, attacks, countermeasures, and
related research trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAC3 Talk About KNOB and BIAS Attacks</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2020/wac320-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2020/wac320-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad to give a talk about the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://francozappa.github.io/project/knob/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KNOB&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://francozappa.github.io/project/bias/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BIAS&lt;/a&gt; attacks
on Bluetooth at the third
&lt;a href=&#34;https://crypto.iacr.org/2020/wac.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Workshop on Attacks in Cryptography (WAC)&lt;/a&gt;
co-located with&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://crypto.iacr.org/2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRYPTO 2020&lt;/a&gt;.
The Workshop will be held
online on Zoom the 16th of August 2020, and my talk will
be from 13:20 to 14:00 (EDT) in the Attacks on Standards session (session IV).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the talk abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bluetooth is a ubiquitous technology for low power wireless
communications. Bluetooth runs on billions of devices including
mobile, wearables, home automation, smart speakers, headsets,
industrial and medical appliances, and vehicles. As a result,
Bluetooth&amp;rsquo;s attack surface is huge and includes significant threats
such as identity thefts, privacy violations, and malicious device
control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bluetooth is a complex technology specified in an open standard. The
standard defines two wireless stacks Bluetooth Classic for high
throughput services (e.g., audio and voice) and Bluetooth Low Energy
(BLE) for very low power services (e.g., localization, and
monitoring). The standard defines security mechanisms to protect the
confidentiality, integrity, and authenticity of Bluetooth
communications. Those mechanisms include pairing to share a long term
key among two devices, and secure session establishment to let two
paired devices negotiate session keys to protect their communication.
A single vulnerability in a standard-compliant security mechanism
translates into billions of exploitable devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk reviews several standard-compliant vulnerabilities that we
recently uncovered on the key negotiation and authentication
mechanisms of Bluetooth Classic and BLE. We also describe how to
exploit such vulnerabilities to perform key negotiation attacks on
Bluetooth Classic and BLE (KNOB attacks, CVE-2019-9506) and
impersonation attacks on Bluetooth Classic (BIAS attacks,
CVE-2020-10135). The attacks are presented together with a detailed
description of the Bluetooth treat model and the affected security
mechanism. We also explain how we implemented such attacks using
low-cost hardware and open-source software and how we evaluated them
on actual devices from the major vendors including Apple, Broadcom,
Cypress, CSR, Google, Intel, Microsoft, and Qualcomm. Finally, we
describe how the Bluetooth standard was amended after the disclosure
of our attacks, our proposed countermeasures, and why most of the
Bluetooth devices are still vulnerable to our attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details about the KNOB and BIAS attacks have a look at the
related research papers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The KNOB is Broken: Exploiting Low Entropy in the Encryption Key
Negotiation of Bluetooth BR/EDR&lt;/em&gt;, USENIX Security 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key Negotiation Downgrade Attacks on Bluetooth and Bluetooth Low Energy&lt;/em&gt;,
ACM TOPS 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;BIAS: Bluetooth Impersonation AttackS&lt;/em&gt;, IEEE S&amp;amp;P 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please join the virtual WAC, and
thanks
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eyalro.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eyal Ronen&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mathyvanhoef.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mathy Vanhoef&lt;/a&gt;
for organizing it and for the invitation!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My PhD Defense at SUTD</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2019/phd-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2019/phd-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Soon I&amp;rsquo;m going to defend my PhD thesis at SUTD. Feel free to join!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date and time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday, 5 July 2019, 10:00 - 11:00 (AM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think Tank 20 (2.305)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Title of the talk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design, Implementation, and Evaluation of Secure Cyber-Physical and Wireless System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of the presentation we will talk about our recent
contributions in the area of wireless systems security.
Wireless systems are used to transmit (sensitive) information and to manage
and monitor systems remotely. In our recent works we focus on three problems
to advance the security of wireless systems:
effectiveness of deployed physical layer features as defense mechanisms,
complexity and accessibility of wireless technologies, and security
evaluations of wireless protocols. Firstly, we present a theoretical and
empirical comparisons between b/n/ac amendments of IEEE 802.11 (WLAN).
Our goal is to estimate and measure whether or not modern physical layer
features, such as MIMO and beamforming, could be used to as defense mechanism.
Afterwards, we will talk about our security analysis of Nearby Connections, a
proprietary API for proximity-based services developed by Google. This API
uses a combination of Bluetooth and Wi-Fi, and it is included in all Android
devices since version 4.0 and all Android Things devices. Our analysis
uncovers the proprietary (security) mechanisms of Nearby Connections and it is
based on our reverse-engineering of its implementation. We demonstrate that
Nearby Connections is vulnerable to critical threats by implementing  attacks
where we maliciously manipulate Nearby Connections and we extend the
connection range to devices that are not nearby. Prior to publication we
disclosed our findings to Google and we suggested them effective
countermeasures. In the last part of the presentation we will summarize our
contributions in the area of cyber-physical systems (CPS). In particular we
will introduce MiniCPS, a toolkit for real-time CPS simulation and emulation
and its related projects and use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
