<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Daniele Antonioli</title>
    <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Daniele Antonioli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Daniele Antonioli</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://francozappa.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>KNOB Attack FAQ</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-faq/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m trying to address some discussion points and misconceptions about the KNOB attack.
Attribution  Researchers from CISPA discovered the KNOB attack
 Partially true. The KNOB attack was discovered by myself (Daniele Antonioli) from SUTD, Nils Ole Tippenhauer from CISPA, and Kasper Rasmussen from the University of Oxford. In particular, I&amp;rsquo;ve identified the vulnerability back in May 2018 while I was working with Kasper on Nearby Connections at the University of Oxford, and I wrote the first exploit in October 2018 while I was visiting Nils (my former advisor at SUTD) at CISPA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KNOB Attack Code for E0 and Slides from USEC19 are Online</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-repo2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-repo2/</guid>
      <description>The code that we developed to validate and brute force E0 encryption keys is online.
The slides of my KNOB attack USEC19 talk are also online. As we can see from the slides, the KNOB attack is not conducted while two Bluetooth devices are pairing, but when two devices are connecting (establishing a new encrypted session). Bluetooth (BR/EDR) is a technology with a pair-once connect-multiple-times paradigm. For example, you pair your smartphone with your car once, and then every day you connect the two and the devices negotiate a new (fresh) encryption key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KNOB Attack Repository is Online</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-repo/</guid>
      <description>Our KNOB repository is online, and it includes our PoC.
For more information visit knobattack.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Negotiation Of Bluetooth (KNOB) Attack</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/knob-announce/</guid>
      <description>The embargo is over! The information about The KNOB is Broken: Exploiting Low Entropy in the Encryption Key Negotiation Of Bluetooth BR/EDR, including our research paper, CVE details, and media coverage, are publicly available at knobattack.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My PhD Defense at SUTD</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/phd-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/phd-defense/</guid>
      <description>Soon I&amp;rsquo;m going to defend my PhD thesis at SUTD. Feel free to join!
Date and time:
 Friday, 5 July 2019, 10:00 - 11:00 (AM)
 Venue:
 Think Tank 20 (2.305)
 Title of the talk:
 Design, Implementation, and Evaluation of Secure Cyber-Physical and Wireless System
 Abstract:
 In the first part of the presentation we will talk about our recent contributions in the area of wireless systems security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NDSS 2019 YouTube video of the presentation</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19-video/</guid>
      <description>My NDSS 2019 presentation of Nearby Threats: Reversing‚ Analyzing‚ and Attacking Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nearby Connections&amp;rdquo; on Android
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NDSS 2019 in San Diego</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19-conf/</guid>
      <description>This week I&amp;rsquo;ve been in San Diego CA for the The Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS) 2019 conference.
I&amp;rsquo;ve presented our paper about Nearby Threats: Reversing, Analyzing, and Attacking Google’s ‘Nearby Connections’ on Android.
Please have a look at the slides, at the, Soft AP manipulation PoC and the reddit thread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: Cyber-Physical System SECurity (CPS-SEC) Workshop 2019</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/cfp-cps-sec19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/cfp-cps-sec19/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve accepted the invitation to join the IEEE CPS-SEC workshop TPC. CPS-SEC is co-located with the IEEE CNS conference . From the official website:
 The IEEE International Workshop on Cyber-Physical Systems Security (CPS-Sec) will be held in conjunction with the IEEE Conference on Communications and Network Security (CNS) 2019 in Washington, D.C., USA, on 10-12 June, 2019.
Nowadays, the correct functioning of information systems represents a fundamental milestone for the well-being of modern economies and societies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NDSS 2019 camera-ready and PoC attack code</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19-cr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19-cr/</guid>
      <description>The camera-ready version of Nearby Threats: Reversing‚ Analyzing‚ and Attacking Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nearby Connections&amp;rdquo; on Android is available here
We also released a proof of concept code to perform the Soft AP manipulation attack. The code was previously disclosed to Google. In summary, the attack allows a malicious Nearby Connections server (advertiser) to redirect a client to a malicious Internet connected access point. As a result the attacker can reconfigure the wireless network interface of the victim via DHCP and gets access to all the Wi-Fi traffic (even traffic from non Nearby Connections applications).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic day_night and search</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/theme-daynight-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/theme-daynight-search/</guid>
      <description>Recently gcushen updated Academic (the theme that I&amp;rsquo;m using to build this website with hugo) with two useful features that I recommend to use: day_night and search.
day_night allows the reader to toggle light and dark color themes for the website. If you look at the top navigation bar on the right you should spot an icon with either a moon (to switch to a dark theme) or a sun (to switch to a light theme).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Paper is Accepted for NDSS 2019</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m very happy to announce that our paper titled Nearby Threats: Reversing‚ Analyzing‚ and Attacking Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nearby Connections&amp;rdquo; on Android has been accepted for the The Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS). Here you can download a pre-print. Here is the list of accepted papers for NDSS 2019 Soon I&amp;rsquo;ll update more material such an exploit PoC code.
Congratulations to Kasper and Nils and thank you for the help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting Researcher at CISPA, University of Saarbrücken</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/cispa-visiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/cispa-visiting/</guid>
      <description>As part of my PhD I&amp;rsquo;ve recently joined as a visiting researcher the CISPA – Helmholtz-Zentrum, Saarbruecken 🇩🇪.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to spend six months there, supervised by Prof. N.O. Tippenhauer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Connect to the SUTD&#39;s eduroam using (Arch) Linux</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/sutd-eduroam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/sutd-eduroam/</guid>
      <description>After the post about connecting to SUTD&amp;rsquo;s VPN is now time to connect eduroam! Again, SUTD&amp;rsquo;s IT support for (Arch) Linux at the time of writing is none.
SUTD runs a setup with only username-password (no certificates required) and the connection can be established using the GUI of NetworkManager. If your WiFi card is on and eduroam is in your range you should see the eduroam SSID on the list of the available WiFi networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Connect to the SUTD&#39;s VPN using (Arch) Linux as a Student</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/sutd-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/sutd-vpn/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently came across the problem of connecting to the SUTD VPN server from overseas. SUTD&amp;rsquo;s IT support for (Arch) Linux at the time of writing is none, and after a bit of research I&amp;rsquo;ve found a quick and easy solution.
SUTD runs Pulse Connect Secure (PCS) server, a commercial solution known as Juniper SSL VPN. Luckily there is an open-source client that supports PCS named OpenConnect. Arch has an openconnect package and a NetworkManager plugin called networkmanager-openconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting Researcher at the University of Oxford</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/oxford-visiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/oxford-visiting/</guid>
      <description>As part of my PhD I&amp;rsquo;ve recently joined as a visiting researcher the Department of Computer Science, University of Oxford 🇬🇧.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to spend around six months there, supervised by Prof. Kasper Rasmussen and co-supervised by Prof. Ivan Martinovic.
I&amp;rsquo;m very excited!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAC 2018</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/sac18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/sac18/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that our paper titled State-Aware Anomaly Detection for Industrial Control Systems has been accepted for the Symposium On Applied Computing (SAC) 2018 conference.
Congratulations to Hamid, and the co-authors!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CANS 2017</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/cans17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/cans17/</guid>
      <description>This week I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Hong Kong for the Cryptology And Network Security Conference (CANS) 2017 conference.
I&amp;rsquo;ve presented our paper about: Practical Evaluation of Passive COTS Eavesdropping in 802.11b/n/ac WLAN.
Here I&amp;rsquo;m sharing some pictures with some new friends:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Institutional Email Issue</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/email-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/email-issues/</guid>
      <description>For some reasons my name_surname@sutd.edu.sg email address was deactivated without notice sometime at the end of October 2017. Unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered it only this week and I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to reactivate it. I apologize if you recently got an error message while trying to send me an email to that address.
Please use the surname.name@gmail.com address instead. I ❤️ ✉️</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S317: MiniCPS Challenges</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/minicps-s3-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 14:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/minicps-s3-code/</guid>
      <description>I recently open-sourced the code that I developed for the MiniCPS challenges for the SWaT Security Showdown (S3) event in 2017.
Here is the code.
The init.sh contains the list of commands that I run on a local testing machine and on the remote AWS instances that we used during the event. The attackers were provided with the VPN credentials to access two different subnetworks in a mixed MiniCPS simulation eg: water treatment (SWaT) and water distribution (WaDI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ST Engineering Poster Award at FIRST Industry Workshop 2017</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/first17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/first17/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that my poster titled Towards high-interaction virtual ICS honeypots-in-a-box won the ST Engineering Poster Award at the FIRST industry workshop, held at SUTD. This is a special gift one day before my 30th birthday! Here I&amp;rsquo;m sharing a picture from the award ceremony:
Congratulations also to Hamid who won one award:
and Eyasu who managed to win two awards:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Science, Technology and Policy Workshop</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/smart17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/smart17/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was selected as a mentor for the cybersecurity track of the Future of Science, Technology and Policy Workshop, organized by SMART. I had the privilege to supervision six graduate and post-graduate colleagues with different backgrounds:
 Jukka Isohätälä from NUS (Physics and CS) Nikhil Mallareddy from MIT (Environmental Engineering) Ioannis Fousekis from ETH (EECS and Economics) Michael Wicki from ETH (Political sciences and Economics) Fabian Willibaldf rom ETH (Environmental Engineering) Jay Prakash from SUTD (EECS)  I&amp;rsquo;m presenting the summary of our activities of day 2 related to cybersecurity organized at my institution SUTD:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>