<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cps-sec | Daniele Antonioli</title>
    <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tag/cps-sec/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://francozappa.github.io/tag/cps-sec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>cps-sec</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Daniele Antonioli</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://francozappa.github.io/images/icon_hufd6449924b8771808a89b636be1cd7b0_295644_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>cps-sec</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tag/cps-sec/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: Cyber-Physical System SECurity (CPS-SEC) Workshop 2019</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/cfp-cps-sec19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/cfp-cps-sec19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve accepted the invitation to join the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://cns2019.ieee-cns.org/workshop/cps-sec-international-workshop-cyber-physical-systems-security&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IEEE CPS-SEC workshop&lt;/a&gt;
TPC. CPS-SEC is co-located with the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://cns2019.ieee-cns.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IEEE CNS conference&lt;/a&gt; .
From the official website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IEEE International Workshop on Cyber-Physical Systems Security (CPS-Sec)
will be held in conjunction with the IEEE Conference on Communications and
Network Security (CNS) 2019 in Washington, D.C., USA, on 10-12 June, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the correct functioning of information systems represents a
fundamental milestone for the well-being of modern economies and societies.
The scientific evolution of digital, analog, and physical components with the
interactions between networks created the Cyber-Physical Systems (CPS). Even
though the benefits of the cyber and physical world interactions are
noticeable, new security challenges have arisen: typical vulnerabilities from
the cyber domain emerged in CPS. Cyber-attacks over CPS pose different
security challenges. In particular, classic Information Technology (IT) cyber
security tools are considered partially or totally ineffective in CPS
scenarios because complex cyber-physical attacks could avoid security
detection methodologies developed specifically for the IT world. The
prevention, detection, and mitigation of cyber-attacks encompass both the
physical and the cyber layers of a system: to this end, approaches to securing
CPS consider techniques adopted in the physical domain and in the cyber space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the success of the previous editions, the IEEE International
Workshop on Cyber-Physical Systems Security 2019 (CPS-Sec 2019) aims to
represent a forum for researchers and practitioners from industry and academia
interested in the areas of CPS security. CPS-Sec 2019 seeks novel submissions
describing practical and theoretical solutions to the cyber-physical security
challenges. A submission may represent any CPS domain, including embedded
systems, Internet of Things (IoT), Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT), SCADA
Systems, Smart-Grid Systems, Critical Infrastructure, Automotive and
Transportation Systems, Medical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important dates:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submission Deadline: 15 March, 2019 (extended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notification of Acceptance: 26 March, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera-Ready: 2 April, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
