<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cfp | Daniele Antonioli</title>
    <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tag/cfp/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://francozappa.github.io/tag/cfp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>cfp</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Daniele Antonioli</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://francozappa.github.io/media/icon_hufd6449924b8771808a89b636be1cd7b0_295644_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>cfp</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tag/cfp/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: JSys System Security</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2022/cfp-jsys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2022/cfp-jsys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jsys.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Systems Research (JSys)&lt;/a&gt;
is a new journal with diamond-access
publication model; that is, papers are free to read, submit, review, and
publish. Its design borrows heavily from similar journals recently created in
the databases, security, and crypto communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently JSys added a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jsys.org/cfp_security/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;system security track&lt;/a&gt; and the first CfP
is open until the 22nd of May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;call-for-papers-system-security&#34;&gt;Call for Papers: System Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;System security covers the intersection between systems research and security
research in particular around the topics of software security, web security,
mobile security, network security, operating system security, and hardware
security. These topics inherently involve systems topics as part of their
mechanisms, policies, or attacks. While attacks are in scope, the focus of
this track is on constructive security, i.e., mitigating and avoiding attacks
along with systematizing knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic of interests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis of network and security protocols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attacks with novel insights, techniques, or results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated security analysis of source code and binaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embedded systems security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language-based security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile systems security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating system security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Program analysis for security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP Workshop on Offensive Technologies (WOOT) 2022</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2022/cfp-woot22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2022/cfp-woot22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The WOOT&#39;22 CFP is open. Please submit and spread the word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;URL: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ieee-security.org/TC/SP2022/WOOT22/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.ieee-security.org/TC/SP2022/WOOT22/index.html&lt;/a&gt;
Submission: &lt;a href=&#34;https://woot22.secpriv.tuwien.ac.at/woot22/paper/new&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://woot22.secpriv.tuwien.ac.at/woot22/paper/new&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Workshop on Offensive Technologies (WOOT) aims to present a broad picture of offense and its contributions, bringing together researchers and practitioners across all areas of computer security. Offensive security has changed from a hobby to an industry. No longer an exercise for isolated enthusiasts, offensive security is today a large-scale operation managed by organized, capitalized actors. Meanwhile, the landscape has shifted: software used by millions is built by startups less than a year old, delivered on mobile phones and surveilled by national signals intelligence agencies. In the field&amp;rsquo;s infancy, offensive security research was conducted separately by industry, independent hackers, or in academia. Collaboration between these groups was difficult. Since 2007, the Workshop on Offensive Technologies (WOOT) has been bringing those communities together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;symposium-topics&#34;&gt;Symposium Topics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer security exposes the differences between the actual mechanisms of
everyday trusted technologies and their models used by developers, architects,
academic researchers, owners, operators, and end users. While being inherently
focused on practice, security also poses questions such as &amp;ldquo;what kind of
computations are and aren&amp;rsquo;t trusted systems capable of?&amp;rdquo; which harken back
to fundamentals of computability. State-of-the-art offense explores these
questions pragmatically, gathering material for generalizations that lead to
better models and more trustworthy systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WOOT provides a forum for high-quality, peer-reviewed work discussing tools
and techniques for attacks. Submissions should reflect the state of the art in
offensive computer security technology, exposing poorly understood mechanisms,
presenting novel attacks, highlighting the limitations of published attacks
and defenses, or surveying the state of offensive operations at scale. WOOT
&amp;lsquo;22 accepts papers in both an academic security context and more applied work
that informs the field about the state of security practice in offensive
techniques. The goal for these submissions is to produce published works that
will guide future work in the field. Submissions will be peer reviewed and
shepherded as appropriate. Submission topics include, but are not limited to,
attacks on and offensive research into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware, including software-based exploitation of hardware vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtualization and the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network and distributed systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser and general client-side security (runtimes, JITs, sandboxing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis of mitigations and automating how they can be bypassed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automating software testing such as fuzzing for novel targets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber-physical systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cryptographic systems (practical attacks on deployed systems)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Malware design, implementation and analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offensive applications of formal methods (solvers, symbolic execution)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;workshop-format&#34;&gt;Workshop Format&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presenters will be authors of accepted papers. There will also be a keynote speaker and a selection of invited speakers. WOOT &amp;lsquo;22 will feature a Best Paper Award and a Best Student Paper Award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that WOOT&#39;22 and other IEEE S&amp;amp;P workshops are planned to be held in person, see the IEEE S&amp;amp;P website for details and updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;regular-submission&#34;&gt;Regular Submission&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WOOT &amp;lsquo;22 welcomes submissions without restrictions of origin. Submissions from academia, independent researchers, students, hackers, and industry are welcome. Are you planning to give a cool talk at Black Hat in August? Got something interesting planned for other non-academic venues later this year? This is exactly the type of work we&amp;rsquo;d like to see at WOOT &amp;lsquo;22. Please submit &amp;ndash; it will also give you a chance to have your work reviewed and to receive suggestions and comments from some of the best researchers in the world. More formal academic offensive security papers are also very welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;systematization-of-knowledge&#34;&gt;Systematization of Knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing the tradition of past years, WOOT &amp;lsquo;22 will be accepting &amp;ldquo;Systematization of Knowledge&amp;rdquo; (SoK) papers. The goal of an SoK paper is to encourage work that evaluates, systematizes, and contextualizes existing knowledge. These papers will prove highly valuable to our community but would not be accepted as refereed papers because they lack novel research contributions. Suitable papers include survey papers that provide useful perspectives on major research areas, papers that support or challenge long-held beliefs with compelling evidence, or papers that provide an extensive and realistic evaluation of competing approaches to solving specific problems. Be sure to select &amp;ldquo;Systematization of Knowledge paper&amp;rdquo; in the submissions system to distinguish it from other paper submissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;submission-requirements&#34;&gt;Submission Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paper submission deadline: Thursday, January 27, 2022, 11:59 AoE (Anywhere on Earth)
Notification date: Thursday, February 27, 2022
Camera-ready paper deadline: Tuesday, March 8, 2022
Workshop date: Thursday, May 26, 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please submit your paper at &lt;a href=&#34;https://woot22.secpriv.tuwien.ac.at/woot22/paper/new&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://woot22.secpriv.tuwien.ac.at/woot22/paper/new&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-to-submit&#34;&gt;What to Submit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submissions must be in PDF format. Papers should be succinct but thorough in presenting the work. The contribution needs to be well motivated, clearly exposed, and compared to the state of the art. Typical research papers are at least 4 pages, and maximum 10 pages long (not counting bibliography and appendix). Yet, papers whose lengths are incommensurate with their contributions will be rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The submission should be formatted in 2-columns, using 10-point Times Roman type on 12-point leading, in a text block of 6.5” x 9”. Please number the pages. Authors must use the IEEE templates, for LaTeX papers this is IEEETran.cls version 1.8b.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submissions are double blind: submissions should be anonymized and avoid obvious self-references (authors are allowed to release technical reports and present their work elsewhere such as at DefCon or BlackHat). Submit papers using the submission form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authors of accepted papers will have to provide a paper for the proceedings following the above guidelines. A shepherd may be assigned to ensure the quality of the proceedings version of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your paper should not be published prior to the event, please notify the chairs. Submissions accompanied by non-disclosure agreement forms will not be considered. Accepted submissions will be treated as confidential prior to publication on the WOOT &amp;lsquo;22 website; rejected submissions will be permanently treated as confidential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;policies-and-contact-information&#34;&gt;Policies and Contact Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simultaneous submission of the same work to multiple competing academic venues, submission of previously published work without substantial novel contributions, or plagiarism constitutes dishonesty or fraud may lead to instant or later rejecion.
Note: Work presented by the authors at industry conferences, such as Black Hat, is not considered to have been &amp;ldquo;previously published&amp;rdquo; for the purposes of WOOT &amp;lsquo;22. We strongly encourage the submission of such work to WOOT &amp;lsquo;22, particularly work that is well suited to a more formal and complete treatment in a published, peer-reviewed setting. In your submission, please do note any previous presentations of the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vulnerability-disclosure&#34;&gt;Vulnerability Disclosure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the submission describes, or otherwise takes advantage of, newly identified vulnerabilities (e.g., software vulnerabilities in a given program or design weaknesses in a hardware system) the authors should disclose these vulnerabilities to the vendors/maintainers of affected software or hardware systems prior to the CFP deadline. When disclosure is necessary, authors should include a statement within their submission and/or final paper about steps taken to fulfill the goal of disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ethical-considerations&#34;&gt;Ethical Considerations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submissions that describe experiments on human subjects, that analyze data derived from human subjects (even anonymized data), or that otherwise may put humans at risk should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disclose whether the research received an approval or waiver from each of the authors’ institutional ethics review boards (e.g., an IRB).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss steps taken to ensure that participants and others who might have been affected by an experiment were treated ethically and with respect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a paper raises significant ethical or legal concerns, including in its handling of personally identifiable information (PII) or other kinds of sensitive data, it might be rejected based on these concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: ACM CPSS 2022</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2022/cfp-cpss22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2022/cfp-cpss22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The call for papers for 8th ACM Cyber-Physical System Security Workshop
(CPSS 2022) held in conjunction with ACM AsiaCCS&#39;22 is closing in 1 month
(December 3, 2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure to submit your awesome CPS security papers :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information see the CPSS &lt;a href=&#34;https://illinois.adsc.com.sg/CPSS2022/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and
its &lt;a href=&#34;https://illinois.adsc.com.sg/CPSS2022/CPSS%20CFP2022.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;call for papers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: 2021 IEEE Workshop on Offensive Technologies (WOOT)</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2021/cfp-woot21/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2021/cfp-woot21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The call for papers for the 2021 IEEE Workshop on Offensive Technologies (WOOT)
is open. Please submit your great research work and spread the word among
attackers 🔥 😄 🔥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the deadlines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abstract registration deadline: Wednesday, January 27, 2021, 11:59 AoE (Anywhere on Earth)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper submission deadline: Friday, January 29, 2021, 11:59 AoE (Anywhere on Earth)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notification date: Monday, March 01, 2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workshop date: Thursday, May 27, 2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submission topics include, but are not limited to, attacks on and offensive research into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware, including software-based exploitation of hardware vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtualization and the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network and distributed systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser and general client-side security (runtimes, JITs, sandboxing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis of mitigations and automating how they can be bypassed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automating software testing such as fuzzing for novel targets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber-physical systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cryptographic systems (practical attacks on deployed systems)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Malware design, implementation and analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offensive applications of formal methods (solvers, symbolic execution)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about the CFP look &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ieee-security.org/TC/SP2021/SPW2021/WOOT21/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: ACM AsiaCCS 2021</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2021/cfp-asiaccs21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2021/cfp-asiaccs21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad to serve as a TPC member for &lt;a href=&#34;https://asiaccs2021.comp.polyu.edu.hk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ACM AsiaCCS 2021&lt;/a&gt;.
The first round of submission deadline is approaching (21 August 2020), indeed
submit your great research works!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are the important dates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1st round deadlines
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper submission: 21 August 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author notification: 24 October 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera ready due to: 25 November 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2st round deadlines
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper submission: 11 December 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author notification: 15 February 2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera ready due to: 15 March 2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference date: June 7-11, 2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSS 2020 Extended Call For Papers</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2020/nss20-cfp-ext/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2020/nss20-cfp-ext/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Network and System Security (NSS) 2020 conference
paper submission deadline has been extended to
&lt;strong&gt;15 September 2020 (Anywhere on Earth)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please submit your research work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find more information in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://nsclab.org/nss2020/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NSS
website&lt;/a&gt; and specifically in the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://nsclab.org/nss2020/cfp.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CFP section&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: Conference on Network and System Security (NSS)</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2020/cfp-nss20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2020/cfp-nss20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad to serve as a TPC member and publicity co-chair for the &lt;em&gt;14th International Conference
on Network and System Security (NSS)&lt;/em&gt;. The conference focuses on network and
system security and welcomes papers from a broad range of topics including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Active Defense Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis, Benchmark of Security Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applied Cryptography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy and Anonymity Technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secure Cryptographic Protocols and Applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security Notions, Approaches, and Paradigms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steganography and Steganalysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blockchain and Cryptocurrency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smart Contract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital Forensics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber Hacking and Protection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intrusion Detection and Prevention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI/Machine Learning Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security Policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security and Privacy in Social Networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trusted Computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watermarking and Digital Rights Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location Privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security For Critical Infrastructures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RFID/NFC Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security Infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security and Privacy For Digital Health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viruses and Malware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intellectual Property Rights Protection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber-Physical Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find more information in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://nsclab.org/nss2020/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Conference
website&lt;/a&gt; and specifically in the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://nsclab.org/nss2020/cfp.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CFP section&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSS 2020 deadlines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper submission &lt;strong&gt;15 July 2020 (Anywhere on Earth)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notification of acceptance &lt;strong&gt;15 August 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera-ready paper submission &lt;strong&gt;20 October 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference location and date &lt;strong&gt;Melbourne Australia, 24–27 November 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: Cyber-Physical System SECurity (CPS-SEC) Workshop 2019</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2019/cfp-cps-sec19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2019/cfp-cps-sec19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve accepted the invitation to join the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cns2019.ieee-cns.org/workshop/cps-sec-international-workshop-cyber-physical-systems-security&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IEEE CPS-SEC workshop&lt;/a&gt;
TPC. CPS-SEC is co-located with the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cns2019.ieee-cns.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IEEE CNS conference&lt;/a&gt; .
From the official website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IEEE International Workshop on Cyber-Physical Systems Security (CPS-Sec)
will be held in conjunction with the IEEE Conference on Communications and
Network Security (CNS) 2019 in Washington, D.C., USA, on 10-12 June, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the correct functioning of information systems represents a
fundamental milestone for the well-being of modern economies and societies.
The scientific evolution of digital, analog, and physical components with the
interactions between networks created the Cyber-Physical Systems (CPS). Even
though the benefits of the cyber and physical world interactions are
noticeable, new security challenges have arisen: typical vulnerabilities from
the cyber domain emerged in CPS. Cyber-attacks over CPS pose different
security challenges. In particular, classic Information Technology (IT) cyber
security tools are considered partially or totally ineffective in CPS
scenarios because complex cyber-physical attacks could avoid security
detection methodologies developed specifically for the IT world. The
prevention, detection, and mitigation of cyber-attacks encompass both the
physical and the cyber layers of a system: to this end, approaches to securing
CPS consider techniques adopted in the physical domain and in the cyber space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the success of the previous editions, the IEEE International
Workshop on Cyber-Physical Systems Security 2019 (CPS-Sec 2019) aims to
represent a forum for researchers and practitioners from industry and academia
interested in the areas of CPS security. CPS-Sec 2019 seeks novel submissions
describing practical and theoretical solutions to the cyber-physical security
challenges. A submission may represent any CPS domain, including embedded
systems, Internet of Things (IoT), Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT), SCADA
Systems, Smart-Grid Systems, Critical Infrastructure, Automotive and
Transportation Systems, Medical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important dates:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submission Deadline: 15 March, 2019 (extended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notification of Acceptance: 26 March, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera-Ready: 2 April, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
