<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ndss on Daniele Antonioli</title>
    <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tags/ndss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ndss on Daniele Antonioli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Daniele Antonioli</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 11:28:36 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://francozappa.github.io/tags/ndss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NDSS 2019 in San Diego</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 11:28:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19-conf/</guid>
      <description>This week I&amp;rsquo;ve been in San Diego CA for the The Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS) 2019 conference.
I&amp;rsquo;ve presented our paper about Nearby Threats: Reversing, Analyzing, and Attacking Google’s ‘Nearby Connections’ on Android.
Please have a look at the slides, and at the Soft AP manipulation PoC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NDSS 2019 camera-ready and PoC attack code</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19-cr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19-cr/</guid>
      <description>The camera-ready version of Nearby Threats: Reversing‚ Analyzing‚ and Attacking Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nearby Connections&amp;rdquo; on Android is available here
We also released a proof of concept code to perform the Soft AP manipulation attack. The code was previously disclosed to Google. In summary, the attack allows a malicious Nearby Connections server (advertiser) to redirect a client to a malicious Internet connected access point. As a result the attacker can reconfigure the wireless network interface of the victim via DHCP and gets access to all the Wi-Fi traffic (even traffic from non Nearby Connections applications).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Paper is Accepted for NDSS 2019</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/ndss19/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m very happy to announce that our paper titled Nearby Threats: Reversing‚ Analyzing‚ and Attacking Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Nearby Connections&amp;rdquo; on Android has been accepted for the The Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS). Here you can download a pre-print. Here is the list of accepted papers for NDSS 2019 Soon I&amp;rsquo;ll update more material such an exploit PoC code.
Congratulations to Kasper and Nils and thank you for the help.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>