<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>de | Daniele Antonioli</title>
    <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tag/de/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://francozappa.github.io/tag/de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>de</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2026 Daniele Antonioli</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://francozappa.github.io/media/icon_hufd6449924b8771808a89b636be1cd7b0_295644_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>de</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tag/de/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ENCOPIA</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/project/encopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/project/encopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;contacts&#34;&gt;Contacts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://encopia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-concept-and-innovation&#34;&gt;Core Concept and Innovation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s IoT devices collect huge amounts of data and share them with cloud
services. In turn, Big Data analytics are used to analyze this data to provide
new services such as predictive maintenance, more efficient routing and
targeted advertisement. As the world becomes pervasively sentient with sensors
placed in all kinds of daily devices, opting out is no longer possible.
Devices like autonomous cars, smart screens and smart glasses will record
personal information of all passersby, resulting in a conflict between
individual privacy rights and the interest of making the benefits of big data
analytics available to society as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure both goals are achievable, great care in the design and development
of the complete IoT system from the device to the cloud service is necessary.
This project aims at automating the verification of privacy goals of IoT
services, from sensor devices all the way into the cloud services — during
development and after deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scientific-and-technological-goals&#34;&gt;Scientific and Technological Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose to use binary analysis methods to make privacy goals testable in an
automated fashion for the complete life cycle of sensitive information. Tools
developed in this project will ensure that sensitive data can be tracked
through programs and services by analyzing the software used and tracking data
flows within them. Automated privacy analysis tools do not exist today. Yet
binary analysis has made great strides in the last years. With a combination
of binary-level function detection and information flow tracking, data can be
traced through applications along its life cycle, tracking its usage and
detecting potential privacy breaches when they occur. By combining
state-of-the-art binary analysis with dynamic data flow tracking in the cloud
through JIT compiler instrumentation, we achieve an end-to-end privacy
tracking of sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-outlook&#34;&gt;Future Outlook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wide availability and sharing of vast amounts of data is necessary to
drive digital innovation and leverage the powerful tools of big data and
machine learning for the future knowledge society. The proposed tools will
enable developers, third-party providers and users to ensure that data is used
as intended and that protective mechanisms such as pseudonymization,
encryption or differential privacy are applied. The researched methods can
also be applied in certification schemes, which are currently under
development under the European Cybersecurity Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;consortium&#34;&gt;Consortium&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Langlauf Security Automation GmbH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Siemens AG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SAP Labs France&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EURECOM, Software and System Security Group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Lübeck, Institute for IT Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
