<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>acns | Daniele Antonioli</title>
    <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tag/acns/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://francozappa.github.io/tag/acns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>acns</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 Daniele Antonioli</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://francozappa.github.io/media/icon_hufd6449924b8771808a89b636be1cd7b0_295644_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>acns</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/tag/acns/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>SecMT&#39;21 Talk About Security of Proximity Services</title>
      <link>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2021/secmt21-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://francozappa.github.io/post/2021/secmt21-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad to give a talk at the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://spritz.math.unipd.it/events/2021/ACNS_Workshop/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SecMT&#39;21&lt;/a&gt;
workshop on mobile system security
co-located with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sulab-sever.u-aizu.ac.jp/ACNS2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ACNS&#39;21&lt;/a&gt;
conference.
Students can register to SecMT for &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt; by filling this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfwNOLR8AJmbJo5F954hTXvhsTfKXE3FvTVFr-OLmLcbWmTyg/viewform&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk title&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is Hard to Secure Mobile Proximity Services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk abstract&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile devices such as phones, tablets, and wearables enable proximity
services on a large scale. These services use wireless technologies (such as
Wi-Fi and Bluetooth) to connect users within a specific range and exchange
information. Proximity information ranges from general-purpose files and
contacts to privacy-preserving COVID-19 proximity identifiers. Since these
services affect millions of mobile users worldwide, their security against
cyber threats is paramount. It is not pleasant if an attacker in proximity (or
even remotely) can eavesdrop on private communication or tamper with personal
data. However, adopting (even essential) security mechanisms for proximity
services is easy in theory but pretty hard in practice. For example, it is
challenging to provide confidentiality and authenticity while at the same time
provide energy-efficient and accurate proximity tracing. On top of that, a
usable proximity service has to scale well with the number of users and
provide the same quality of services across different software and hardware
ecosystems (e.g., Android and iOS) and usage condition (e.g., indoor and
outdoor). In this talk, we look at two commercial proximity services. First,
Google&amp;rsquo;s Nearby Connections (NC) is an API to connect Android devices using a
combination of Wi-Fi and Bluetooth and without requiring an Internet
connection. Second, Google/Apple&amp;rsquo;s Exposure Notification (EN) framework. EN
powers most COVID-19 contact-tracing mobile applications in Europe, including
the ones used in Italy, Germany, and Switzerland. Throughout the talk, the
audience will learn, among others, real-world proximity services&#39;
architectures, pitfalls, vulnerabilities, attacks, countermeasures, and
related research trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
